Victor Swanberg

SUMMARY

Offering over five years experience working in software development, web content management, office management, retail and customer service.

Currently pursuing my under-graduate in Computer Science Information Technology degree, I am a strong planner and problem solver who readily adapts to change, works independently and exceeds expectations. I am a proven team leader, able to juggle multiple priorities and meet tight deadlines without compromising quality.

SKILLS

Communication	Web Content Developer	eLearning Developer	Sales
Project Management	Management	Database Administration	HTML5
Inventory Management	Information Technology	Storyline/Captivate	LMS/LCMS
Performance coaching	Customer service	Human resources	Consulting

EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER Sublime Media

2017-2022

Creative agency in Seattle, Washington that develops custom learning solutions for large, fortune 500 companies.

- Developed custom eLearning courses by combining authoring tools with custom markup languages to create an engaging end user experience
- Produced courses that met brand guidelines for clients including Microsoft, Amazon, and Ancestry
- Worked with clients, SMES, and stakeholders to deliver solutions that meet high expectations and tight deadlines
- Implemented agile project management methodology
- Delivered projects on-time and under budget
- Uploaded packages to multiple learner manager systems
- Worked with client IT teams to troubleshoot issues
- Implemented Quality Assurance through multiple stages including alpha, beta, and RC.
- Performed accessibility testing and 502 compliance
- Applied creative problem solving to efficiently manage resources
- Worked effectively and collaborative with team members

Victor Swanberg

 Implemented knowledge from all my different positions to implement and document business process improvements

ASSISTANT ACCOUNT MANAGER Philip J. Boren, Inc.

2017-2018

Manufacturing and big-box retail consultant in Bellevue, Washington.

- Provided exemplary customer service and communication on different platforms to multiple accounts nationwide
- Processed purchase orders and return authorizations on multiple portals
- processed all software and hardware issues that the staff experienced.
- Maintained company website and VOIP phone systems.
- Assembled deployment workstations for new employees.
- Managed and administered company inventory and assets in multiple storage units, scheduled meetings
- Created and implemented new business processes and utilized programs to make processes more efficient.

STORE MANAGER Finish Line, Lynnwood

2015-2017

National Retail chain that sells athletic shoes, apparel and accessories

- Managed retail store overseeing 1.8 million dollars in annual sales
- Used sales metrics to manage store for operational excellence
- Created and managed a team of 10 individuals with a focus on high customer service to execute the business operations required.
- Managed payroll with applications like Oracle, Kronos, and Payroll systems
- Used performance coaching to develop employee sales skills with positive results
- Lead store to provide excellent customer service to XX with the intention to create a perfect experience for any customer no matter the outcome.

DESKTOP SUPPORT SPECIALIST Intern Edmonds Community College 2014

Internship at public community college in Edmonds, WA

- Installed different software on users' computers, in accordance to their specific requirements and industry standards.
- Connected peripherals and auxiliary equipment to main computers and configured them appropriately.
- Monitored network flow and ensured that all computers were properly secured by installing antivirus and malware software
- Created tickets for technical problems that could not be resolved at a tier 1 level by escalating them to information technology managers

Victor Swanberg

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts, Computer Information Systems

2015

Edmonds Community College

Coursework included:

- Human-computer interactions in hardware support
- Databases and data management using SQL
- Networking and Communications using MS Server R2
- Software Development using Visual Basic and Visio
- System Administration using MS office enterprises
- Systems Security utilizing Anti-virus software and Active Directory administration.

Professional Certifications

- ATA Computer Information Systems 2017
- Desktop Support Specialist Certificate 2016
- Database Management Certificate 2016
- Network Security Certificate 2016